<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="//maxxholmes.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="//maxxholmes.github.io//" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-11T20:46:44+01:00</updated><id>//maxxholmes.github.io//feed.xml</id><title type="html">Maxx Holmes</title><subtitle>Welcome to my website about science, programming, and my PhD journey.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">#100DaysOfCode - Day: 0</title><link href="//maxxholmes.github.io//100daysofcode/2020/05/10/100DaysOfCode-Day0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="#100DaysOfCode - Day: 0" /><published>2020-05-10T23:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-10T23:00:00+01:00</updated><id>//maxxholmes.github.io//100daysofcode/2020/05/10/#100DaysOfCode-Day0</id><content type="html" xml:base="//maxxholmes.github.io//100daysofcode/2020/05/10/100DaysOfCode-Day0.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-0-may-10th-2020&quot;&gt;Day 0: May 10th, 2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to commit to the &lt;strong&gt;#100DaysOfCode&lt;/strong&gt; challenge to improve myself and get ready for the “real world” once I finish my PhD and look for my first career position!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Goals:&lt;/strong&gt; I already can code in some capacity in Python, R, Matlab and C++ but not as strongly as I would like. I have undertaken a BSc Physics, MSc Data Science and am currently undergoing a PhD where I have learned scientific programming to the point where I can implement mathematical models, produce data analysis and visualisations and basic machine learning. I have little to no experience in html, css or js other than some brief skills I learned developing a personal website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goals therefore are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To improve my scientific programming skills by exploring new methods and problem solving&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn basic html/css/js skills through web development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will host or link everything I do on my github &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MaxxHolmes/&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MaxxHolmes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, twitter &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MaxxSci&quot;&gt;@MaxxSci&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and on this website I built over the last few days!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my first week - I will be solving &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://projecteuler.net/&quot;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; problems to improve my python skills, while I develop this website to be able to host the solutions to those problems, as well as finishing the Projects/Publications/Contact Me pages. I will be using HTML, CSS and JS to do this, and the Jekyll framework to automate the blog settings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Day 0: May 10th, 2020</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Personal Website</title><link href="//maxxholmes.github.io//general/2020/05/06/My-Personal-Website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Personal Website" /><published>2020-05-06T23:42:56+01:00</published><updated>2020-05-06T23:42:56+01:00</updated><id>//maxxholmes.github.io//general/2020/05/06/My-Personal-Website</id><content type="html" xml:base="//maxxholmes.github.io//general/2020/05/06/My-Personal-Website.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello! I’m Maxx Holmes, and welcome to my website!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed this website as a personal project to widen my repertoire of skills, and to develop a platform for my online presence as I finish my PhD and go out into the “real world”, whatever that is. I took an online template from Pixelarity and tailored it to my needs using Jekyll to host a blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This first post will serve as an introduction to myself, my interests and the kind of content to expect from this website. Pictured above is the first international conference I ever attended - Heart by Numbers 2018, a Biophysical Society Conference in Berlin, Germany. You can see my big head poking out of the back of the crowd. This was my first real experience networking and presenting my research to a large audience - and it was an excellent experience - but this and other conferences have left me with the important lesson of how important networking and presence is within scientific and academic careers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently in the third year of my doctoral studies in the Leeds Computational Physiology Lab, where my thesis focuses on developing and using computational models and tools to dissect the multi-scale mechanisms underlying cardiac arrhythmias - which is quite a substantial jump from my previous degrees of BSc Physics and MSc Data Science! My interests have always leaned towards the geekier, technical side: gaming, programming, music, cooking and of course, science - each of which can be dissected, torn apart and studied piece by piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intention of these blog posts is to provide an insight into what a computational PhD is like, some informative guides on what I consider to be essential programming skills for scientists, and some personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of academic pursuits, I have also previously been a “semi-professional” gamer, having placed top 6 and above in several UK LAN events for DotA 2 and Guitar Hero 3, and I am current a BHF volunteer. The British Heart Foundation is also something very close to my heart and as such I’m a registered volunteer of the BHF, and trained in CPR and First Aid. I have acted as the treasurer of LUU Heart Beats, the first student-led BHF fundraising group of it’s kind for it’s initial and secondary year 2019/2020, where we have won several awards at Leeds Student Union’s Riley Awards for the Best New Society (2019), Best Volunteering Society (2020) and Best Charity Event (2020).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a solid first post, I reckon. I hope you’re all staying safe and staying home. Peace xo&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello! I’m Maxx Holmes, and welcome to my website!</summary></entry></feed>